<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codify Best Practice on Amazon SageMaker Workshop</title>
    <link>/security_for_sysops/best_practice.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codify Best Practice on Amazon SageMaker Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/security_for_sysops/best_practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Service with Guard Rails</title>
      <link>/security_for_sysops/best_practice/service_catalog.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/security_for_sysops/best_practice/service_catalog.html</guid>
      <description>Allowing users in the cloud to self-service and provision cloud resources on-demand is a powerful enabler for project teams but can be a concern from an operational risk perspective. However, if you can empower your developers to self-service, while enforcing guard rails and best practice, then the operational and security teams will also benefit. With enforced guard rails and best practice you can be confident that, while developers are creating resources they need, they are doing so in a manner that is inline with your policies and requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1: Best Practice as Code</title>
      <link>/security_for_sysops/best_practice/best_practice_lab.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/security_for_sysops/best_practice/best_practice_lab.html</guid>
      <description>Before you can begin creating templates for deployment by the Project Administration team you will need a shared services VPC to host a Python package mirror (PyPI) for use by data science teams. The mirror will host a collection of approved Python packages. The concept of a shared services VPC or PyPI mirror is not something that is detailed in this workshop, and is partially assumed as common practice among many AWS customers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
