<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Amazon SageMaker Workshop</title>
    <link>/introduction.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Amazon SageMaker Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/introduction/concepts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/concepts.html</guid>
      <description>This section describes a typical machine learning workflow and summarizes how you accomplish those tasks with Amazon SageMaker.
In machine learning, you &amp;ldquo;teach&amp;rdquo; a computer to make predictions, or inferences. First, you use an algorithm and example data to train a model. Then you integrate your model into your application to generate inferences in real time and at scale. In a production environment, a model typically learns from millions of example data items and produces inferences in hundreds to less than 20 milliseconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Notebook Instance</title>
      <link>/introduction/notebook.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/introduction/notebook.html</guid>
      <description>SageMaker provides hosted Jupyter notebooks that require no setup, so you can begin processing your training data sets immediately. With a few clicks in the SageMaker console, you can create a fully managed notebook instance, pre-loaded with useful libraries for machine learning. You need only add your data.
You&amp;rsquo;ll start by creating an Amazon S3 bucket that will be used throughout the workshop. You&amp;rsquo;ll then create a SageMaker notebook instance, which you will use for the other workshop modules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
